Jason Woodson

jwoodson2014@gmail.com | (804)-921-2290 | https://jwoodson2014.github.io/home/

Experience

University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA

Boe Research Fellow, May 2022 – August 2022

- Scraped and cleaned six seasons worth of data on Formula 1 racing
- Built and trained a model that recommends successful tire strategies for drivers based on factors such as tire choice, race laps, weather, etc.
- Final model achieved an accuracy and precision of 71% and 68%, respectively
- https://tippie.uiowa.edu/news/2022/08/bringing-moneyball-f1-racing
- Skills: R, Advanced Microsoft Excel, Orange

KPMG LLP, Washington, D.C.

Deal Advisory & Strategy Senior Associate, October 2020 – August 2021

- Advised clients on strategies for the taxable consequences of collateralized loan obligations and other fixed income securities, including risk retention strategies related to the Dodd-Frank Act and the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act
- Assisted in the development of KPMG's first internal, cloud-based processing system used to automate processes around analyzing cash flows of fixed income securities to advise clients more accurately on tax planning matters over the life of collateralized loan obligations
- Led the implementation of functions within the system to automate manual processes such as PDF text extraction and auto-generating summary templates that increased productivity by upwards of 35%
- Oversaw the work of five first and second year associates while assuring the timely completion of deliverables for over 50 deals within a 3-month period
- Responsible for maintaining project budgets to meet strict profit margin goals set by directors and partners
- Skills: Python, VBA Programming, Advanced Microsoft Excel, Alteryx

Deal Advisory & Strategy Associate, October 2018 - October 2020

- Analyzed complex cash flows and transactions, sometimes in excess of 10,000, for the tax planning and reporting for collateralized loan obligation (CLO) issuers, including clients with AUM north of \$10 billion
- Skills: VBA Programming, Advanced Microsoft Excel

Education

M.S. Business Analytics – University of Iowa *December 2022*

B.S. Finance – Virginia Tech *May 2018*

B.S. Accounting – Virginia Tech *May 2018*

Background

Innovative thinker with an extremely strong work ethic and desire to continuously learn. Three years of professional consulting experience and an extensive background of working with large amounts of data to make smart, calculated decisions. Currently pursuing a Master's in Business Analytics at the University of Iowa, graduating in December 2022, and looking for a role in data science.

General Skills

Data Science Rela		elational Databases
Data Preprocessing		Sentiment Analysis
Web Scraping		Data Visualization
Machine Learning		Cloud Computing

Technical Skills

Database/Server:

Oracle SQL, Databricks SQL

Programming Languages:

Python, R Programming, SQL, HTML, SparkR

Other Software/Tools:

Tableau, Alteryx, Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Excel, JMP, Orange

Certifications

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Expected December 2022

Certified Public Accountant November 2019 – June 2022